eduref.org 2017-02-12

# The Educator's Reference Desk: Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting the Educator's Reference Desk web site and reviewing our privacy policy.  Our policy is simple: we collect no personal information about you unless you choose to provide that information to us.  We do not give, share, sell, or transfer any personal information to a third party. 

###  Non-Personal Information We Record

When you browse through the web site, read pages, or download information, our web site's operating system will automatically record some general information about your visit. 

###  During your visit, our web operating system will record:

1\. The Internet domain for your internet service, such as "xschool.edu", if you connect from a school or other educational institution, or "xcompany.com" if you connect using a private Internet access account. 

2.  The type of web browser (such as "Netscape version x" or "Internet Explorer version x") that you are using. 

3.  The type of operating system that you use (such as Macintosh, Unix, or Windows). 

4.  The date and time you visit our site, and the web pages that you visit on our site. 

5.  The address of the previous web site you were visiting, if you linked to us from another web site. 

We use this information for statistical analysis, to help us make our site more useful to visitors.  Our system does not record personal information about individuals. 

###  Information Collected from Interactive Forms

We ask you to voluntarily submit personal information (such as your e-mail address, name, affiliation, etc.) on our lesson plan submission form.  If your lesson plan is accepted, that information will be posted along with the lesson plan on our web site. We may contact you if we have a question about your lesson. 

###  Site Security and Intrusion Detection

For security purposes and to make sure this service remains available to all users, our web operating system collects information that could help identify someone making unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise damage this website. 

Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, we make no other attempts to identify individual users or their usage habits. We only use raw monitoring data logs for determining trends in usage patterns and in diagnosing systems problems. 

###  Links to Other Sites

Our policy discloses the privacy practices for the Educator's Reference Desk web site, but we do provide links to other web sites. When you leave the Educator's Reference Desk web site (http://www.eduref.org), you will be going to sites that are beyond our control. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information. The privacy policies and procedures described here for the Educator's Reference Desk do not apply to any external links. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of any site you link to from ours, especially if you share any personal information. 

**For more information** on privacy on the Internet and in the electronic age, see: 

* Privacy Forum   
<http://www.vortex.com/privacy.html>[](http://www.vortex.com/privacy.html)

* Center for Democracy and Technology Privacy Issues   
<http://www.cdt.org/>[](http://www.cdt.org/)

* Electronic Privacy Information Center   
<http://www.epic.org/>

Thanks again for visiting the Educator's Reference Desk web site!
